here from Dubai from the token 24/9 conference.
Kelvin, thank you for being with us on the Crypto Weekly Show.
Happy to be here.
Kelvin, I will talk about the whole range of topics this morning, but let me start first
about this discussion that was happening with the interests you're seeing from investors
when it comes to crypto asset management products.
Are you seeing a lot of interest from retail customers, a lot of institutional customers,
and what the products are you seeing demand for?
I mean, for us, primarily, what we do really caters to high net worth investors as well
as institutional investors rather than retail investors.
And we're seeing a lot of interest from many of the funnel funds, as well as family offices
that want to explore the asset class and look for strategies that's beyond plain vanilla
ETF strategies, right?
I think retail investors are also interested in the asset class, but the interest sort
of comes and goes depending on what's interesting and what is the flavor of the month or quarter.
So, Kelvin, from a strategy perspective, what type of strategy are you seeing demand from
these institutional investors?
Well, first of all, we're definitely seeing strong interest in the ETF products, and you
can see that in the flow data, right, but beyond the ETF products, institutions are starting
to branch out into other strategies, right?
So they're interested to look at the broader array of altcoins that's available to invest
in.
They're interested in market neutral strategies where you are investing in crypto assets,
but you have less volatility and generally higher returns than traditional asset classes.
And then we're also seeing interest, obviously, in the early stage venture strategy, and that's
been something that's been happening for quite a number of years.
So the fundamental strategy, do you really believe in crypto?
It's possible to run a fundamental long-only strategy, considering there's a lot of macro
news, a lot of retail, there's a lot of buzz, how do you even run a fundamental long-by
strategy?
That's a great question.
Well, I spent 20 years in Tritphi, where I was initially a sell-side analyst, and ultimately,
I also moved to hedge fund to do a fundamental equity long short.
And so most of my career sort of centered around understanding company fundamentals and
picking good assets to invest in.
And when I first encountered crypto in 2017, one in Tritmi was when I look at the movement
of these tokens, they respond to news events and catalysts and so on and so forth, very
much like the way stocks behave.
And I think back then, a lot of people believed it was all entirely speculation, but what
I saw was very different.
And so we started going down that rabbit hole and started looking for data that we could
use to build a fundamental analysis.
So we went on-chain, we extracted data on all of these protocols and really used the
traditional fundamental frameworks to evaluate these tokens and if you look at returns that
are fund is generated and how it's outperformed the major assets like Bitcoin and Ethereum,
you can see that the strategy actually works.
But what actually, when you look at these, like the different metrics you're getting
on-chain, are there any of them that you find that I've been particularly useful, whether
determining the quality or the potential or the usability and adoption, the potential
of a certain L1 or any different token?
Obviously, it varies from project to project and asset to asset and depending on what project
you're looking at, the metrics will be different.
So for the L1s, obviously the amount of transaction volume and the amount of fees the L1 generates
is the key metric for something like D5 protocol, like a DAX or a landing protocol, the amount
of volumes that they do and the fees they're able to clip on those transactions is the
main thing because that drives their top line.
And so it varies for every different asset.
And what we talked about, we were talking earlier about the venture space, right?
When you look at the future VC funds in crypto, there's obviously the whole world of liquid
tokens and obviously the whole traditional VC funds that are there, do you believe actually
having VC funds in crypto makes sense or do you believe it's more liquid token strategies
that we're going to see in the future, just considering how the value creation happens
in a lot of these projects?
So I guess for liquid funds, typically we want to invest in assets in a liquid, right?
So not something that's very early stage where we can't trade in and out of because liquid
funds typically have monthly redemption windows and so we need to be able to buy and sell
easily and therefore even though we started as a liquid fund before we delve into the
venture strategies, these very early stage projects are not really appropriate for liquid
funds.
So that's why you need venture funds.
And I think venture funds sort of fulfill a role in crypto because we have a lot of projects
and a lot of founders that are raising capital and many of them are just starting out with
an idea and maybe a small team and then really need investors that can give them risk capital
and in many cases, expect them to fail and be with them on a journey for four or five
years or longer.
I mean, the big question though is there's been obviously a lot of noise recently with
these various tokens.
We've seen the incidents like Magtra and all the noise that happened there, there's been
a lot of other incidents happen as well in the space from the FDUSDP peg and what's your
view on where we are from comes to maturity level of these L1s and these liquid tokens
in the market.
I would say the ecosystem in general is still early and we don't even have a proper regulatory
framework in most places including the US which is the biggest and deepest capital market.
And so because of that, there are no set of rules when it comes to when the project's
ready for listing and what are the criteria they need to be met in order for projects
to be listed.
So the exchanges apply an arbitrary framework to that and so there are no clear standards
and that's why we have these events from time to time where either there's a rock pool or
you see evaluations that don't make sense or a fundamental perspective.
But I think that's going to change as regulations get into place and we have clearer standards
of what projects need to deliver in order to get listed and as we get more institutional
capital coming into the space as well, I think all of those things will start to become more
orderly.
Let's talk about sectors.
For example, I know you have a DFI fund and you have one that is more of the gaming
vertical, what a particular vertical do you see having a lot of potential upside in the
next one or two years and why?
Well, I think I mean, DFI sort of had a big sort of rally back in 2020, right?
And that was sort of the event that catalyzed DFI and brought all the innovators and all
the capital into DFI.
And so we've seen a very strong growth in DFI over the last three to five years.
But DFI has gotten the stage where I think the underlying building blocks of DFI are
already there and the marginal innovation is quite limited.
And then we saw the same thing happen with gaming 2021.
I think this cycle, some of the newer areas that are interesting, areas like AI, obviously,
there's a lot of investments going there and people are excited about the future of AI.
And then the other area I would say that is quite interesting is deep in where we see
a lot of startups innovating, the centralized physical infrastructure, definitely in the
area to watch there.
Thank you very much, Calvin, for being with us.
So that was Calvin Cole, the co-founder of Spartan Group, right here from Dubai.
Thank you, Calvin.
Thanks for your children prepared for the future of money.
Order decoding crypto with Henry and Hodler, the number one new release kids book on Amazon.